{
	"name": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice",
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": "Which of the following is not a component of the Apgar score?\n\nA. Pulse\nB. Body size\nC. Activity\nD. Grimace\nSee Neonatal Assessment and Resuscitation",
			"back": "Body size"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": "An infant is premature if it:\n\nA. is born before 38 weeks’ gestation or weighs less than 6 pounds.\nB. weighs less than 5 pounds or is born before 36 weeks’ gestation.\nC. is born before 40 weeks’ gestation or weighs less than 7 pounds.\nD. weighs less than 5.5 pounds or is born before 37 weeks’ gestation.\nSee Complicated Delivery Emergencies",
			"back": "weighs less than 5 pounds or is born before 36 weeks’ gestation."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": "The amniotic fluid serves to:\n\nA. assist in fetal development.\nB. insulate and protect the fetus.\nC. remove viruses from the fetus.\nD. transfer oxygen to the fetus.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology of the Female Reproductive System",
			"back": "insulate and protect the fetus."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": "Eclampsia is most accurately defined as:\n\nA. high levels of protein in the patient’s urine.\nB. seizures that result from severe hypertension.\nC. a blood pressure greater than 140/90 mm Hg.\nD. hypertension in the 20th week of pregnancy.\nSee Complications of Pregnancy",
			"back": "seizures that result from severe hypertension."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": "By the 20th week of pregnancy, the uterus is typically at or above the level of the mother’s:\n\nA. pubic bone.\nB. xiphoid process.\nC. belly button.\nD. superior diaphragm.\nSee Normal Changes in Pregnancy",
			"back": "belly button."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": "The term primigravida refers to a woman who:\n\nA. has had only one live birth.\nB. has never been pregnant.\nC. is pregnant for the first time.\nD. has had more than one live baby.\nSee Stages of Labor",
			"back": "is pregnant for the first time."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": "Pregnant women are advised to take iron supplements, such as prenatal vitamins, because:\n\nA. pregnancy causes an increased number of red blood cells, which predisposes the mother to anemia.\nB. the blood naturally thins during pregnancy, which predisposes the mother to severe bleeding.\nC. iron makes the blood clot faster, which protects the mother from excessive bleeding during delivery.\nD. white blood cells decrease during pregnancy, which increases the mother’s risk of an infection.\nSee Normal Changes in Pregnancy",
			"back": "pregnancy causes an increased number of red blood cells, which predisposes the mother to anemia."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": "In contrast to a full-term infant, a premature infant:\n\nA. has an even proportionately larger head.\nB. retains heat better because of excess body hair.\nC. is often covered with excess vernix material.\nD. is one who is born before 38 weeks’ gestation.\nSee Complicated Delivery Emergencies",
			"back": "has an even proportionately larger head."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": "A newborn infant will usually begin breathing spontaneously within _______ seconds following birth.\n\nA. 3 to 5\nB. 15 to 30\nC. 30 to 60\nD. 5 to 10\nSee Neonatal Assessment and Resuscitation",
			"back": "15 to 30"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": "A pregnant trauma patient might lose a significant amount of blood before showing signs of shock because:\n\nA. pregnancy causes vasodilation and a lower blood pressure.\nB. pregnant patients can dramatically increase their heart rate.\nC. pregnant patients have an overall increase in blood volume.\nD. blood is shunted to the uterus and fetus during major trauma.\nSee Special Considerations for Trauma and Pregnancy",
			"back": "pregnant patients have an overall increase in blood volume."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": "The umbilical cord:\n\nA. separates from the placenta shortly after birth.\nB. contains two veins and one large umbilical artery.\nC. carries oxygen to the baby via the umbilical vein.\nD. carries blood away from the baby via the artery.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology of the Female Reproductive System",
			"back": "carries oxygen to the baby via the umbilical vein."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": "Which of the following occurs during true labor?\n\nA. Uterine contractions last about 10 seconds.\nB. The uterus becomes very soft and movable.\nC. Uterine contractions become more regular.\nD. Uterine contractions decrease in intensity.\nSee Stages of Labor",
			"back": "Uterine contractions become more regular."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": "When determining the frequency of contractions, you should time the contractions from the:\n\nA. end of one to the start of the next.\nB. end of one to the end of the next.\nC. start of one to the start of the next.\nD. start of one to the end of the next.\nSee Normal Delivery Management",
			"back": "start of one to the start of the next."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": "Which of the following statements regarding a breech presentation is correct?\n\nA. Breech deliveries occur rapidly, so the EMT should deliver at the scene.\nB. It is impossible to deliver a breech presentation in the prehospital setting.\nC. A breech presentation occurs when the buttocks are the presenting part.\nD. There is minimal risk of trauma to the infant with a breech presentation.\nSee Complicated Delivery Emergencies",
			"back": "A breech presentation occurs when the buttocks are the presenting part."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": "A precipitous labor and delivery is most common in women who:\n\nA. have delivered a baby before.\nB. have gestational diabetes.\nC. are pregnant for the first time.\nD. are younger than 30 years of age.\nSee Normal Delivery Management",
			"back": "have delivered a baby before."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": "Fetal complications associated with drug- or alcohol-addicted mothers include all of the following, except:\n\nA. low birth weight.\nB. premature delivery.\nC. profound tachycardia.\nD. respiratory depression.\nSee Complications of Pregnancy",
			"back": "profound tachycardia."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": "Which of the following is an indication of imminent birth?\n\nA. Expulsion of the mucus plug from the vagina\nB. Crowning of the baby’s head\nC. Irregular contractions lasting 10 minutes\nD. Rupture of the amniotic sac\nSee Normal Delivery Management",
			"back": "Crowning of the baby’s head"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": "After a baby is born, it is important to:\n\nA. ensure that it is thoroughly dried and warmed.\nB. position it so that its head is higher than its body.\nC. immediately clamp and cut the umbilical cord.\nD. cool the infant to stimulate effective breathing.\nSee Normal Delivery Management",
			"back": "ensure that it is thoroughly dried and warmed."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": "In contrast to abruptio placenta, placenta previa:\n\nA. might present without significant abdominal pain.\nB. might not present with heavy vaginal bleeding.\nC. is typically associated with severe abdominal pain.\nD. is caused by hypertension or abdominal trauma.\nSee Complications of Pregnancy",
			"back": "might present without significant abdominal pain."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-34-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": "Common interventions used to stimulate spontaneous respirations in the newborn include all of the following, except:\n\nA. thorough drying with a towel.\nB. suctioning of the upper airway.\nC. some form of tactile stimulation.\nD. positive-pressure ventilations.\nSee Neonatal Assessment and Resuscitation",
			"back": "positive-pressure ventilations."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-34",
		"label": "Chapter 34"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}